Hey, get up, Dante!
What time is it?
I'm sorry I'm late for our meeting.
Our client's train broke down along the way.
--Tony...
--Huh?
It's me, Earnest. Don't you remember me?
How do you remember
someone you've never met before?
Just the way you speak,
you're Tony, all right.
No doubt about it.
Huh?
I can understand why you'd
rather not remember all of that.
That was a terrible event...
But at last, I can clear
you and your mother's names!
I found evidence!
Evidence that it was all caused by a devil!
There you go.
Really... What is all this about?
You were late, and then
what you brought wasn't a job...
And what the heck was that guy talking about?
I thought you'd be interested.
Well, when he's saying a
bunch of stuff like that...
Twenty years ago, in a small
port town called Morris Island,
there was a fire that
wiped out the whole town.
The majority of the townspeople died
in the fire, leaving only a few survivors.
But afterwards, some of the
survivors gave testimonials saying
that an army of devils had attacked
the town before the fire broke out.
But nobody would believe their stories.
I suppose not...
That guy who was here
was one of those survivors.
As was this "Tony"?
And his mother.
So what was the whole
"clearing their names" thing about?
People said Tony's mother was
responsible for setting that fire.
She was apparently treated
pretty badly because of that.
So, what ended up happening to that mother?
She took young Tony and
they fled from the town.
And he thinks I was this Tony?
Ridiculous. What would make you
think that I could be this "Tony"?
I got a phone call.
Someone saying "I want you to arrange a
meeting for me with Tony the Devil Hunter."
You're the only devil hunter that I know...
Dante, are you sure the name
"Tony" doesn't ring any bells for you?
Welcome home, Tony.
Morrison called me.
So you've come back to us.
That's not really what I'm doing--
I know.
I'm still glad that you've come.
Come on. It's this way.
I've said it before, but I'm not Tony.
I can understand wanting to keep
your name on the down-low here.
But you don't have anything to worry about.
There aren't many left here that
know what happened 20 years ago.
So much so that I get treated as an eccentric
for still wanting to clarify
what really happened.
I don't care one way or
the other. Who was it?
Huh?
Who was it that you heard about me from?
Very few people know
what it is that I actually do.
Oh... You mean about being a devil hunter?
I just happened to hear about it
from a guy in one of the circus tents.
All right, take me to that circus tent.
Huh?
Okay, then.
Of course, it's you.
Is that the game you want to play?
Why would you pull a gun here?
Just saying a little "hello."
You've really toughened up.
It looks like the circus is on holiday today.
Let's go!
Our teacher will be so happy to see you.
Teacher?
If you wanna play, you
come looking for me yourself.
Ms. Margaret,
Tony's here!
Tony!
No, this guy's just calling me that.
It seems like Tony doesn't want
anyone to know who he really is.
Can you blame him?
So, how is your mother doing?
She's dead. She's been dead for a long time.
Is that so? I'm sorry to hear that.
I wished back then that I
could have helped your mother
rid herself of some of the
suffering and sadness she endured.
Teacher, he works as a
devil hunter at present.
I see. You've really come a long
way, haven't you, Tony? Good for you.
Teacher... It's fine, isn't it?
We can tell Tony now, can't we?
Of course, that's why we
had him come here, after all.
This is to atone for making you and
your mother suffer so much back then.
What are you talking about?
I told you before.
That I finally found evidence!
Evidence that the destruction of our town
was not caused by a person, but by a devil!
--Ruins?
--Yes.
You're not planning to summon
the devil from those ruins, are you?
You're good. You see through my whole plan.
Did the guy in the circus
tent tell you about that, too?
The meaning of the ruins,
how to summon the devil...
The guy who gave you the idea
that I'm Tony told you everything.
What's wrong with that?
I really did get to see you, after all.
The important thing is clearing
you and your mother's names.
Brings back memories, doesn't it?
Well, this toast's a little delayed,
but here's to seeing you again.
Oh, you're back?
Welcome home.
Let me introduce you. This is my wife, Elise.
He's a lot bigger than you
made him out to be in your stories.
Well, of course he is.
All my stories are from back
when we were kids. Really...
Oh, I guess you're right. Sorry.
Oh, and I'll start preparing dinner.
You don't have to do that right now.
You just got back from work.
But...
Why don't you just stay here
and have a chat with Tony, okay?
You'll have to forgive me. This is the
first time I've met one of Earnest's friends...
You don't have to worry
about me. I'm used to being alone.
Everyone in this town
says that Earnest is eccentric.
Even his students call him strange.
Even after all the work he's done to
emulate Ms. Margaret and become a teacher.
What do you think?
Me, I wish he would just forget the past.
So tell him that.
I have... I don't know how many times.
The truth is, even he was
on the verge of giving up.
Ms. Margaret has fallen sick and all...
But then one day he came home ecstatic,
saying that he could clear up that
event that happened 20 years ago
and that he would be able to meet you.
In his mind, you are something special.
I've heard so many stories
about you from him.
Always saying "Tony is
the most wonderful guy"...
Once he starts talking about you,
he could go on all night long
and still have more to tell.
I know everything there is to know about you.
Oh, wait. There is one
thing I don't know about you.
The promise you two made...
Promise?
Yes. He says, "There's no way I
can break a promise with Tony,"
so the only thing he won't tell
me even now is the location
of that treasure box you two buried together.
You know how kids think,
it's probably hidden somewhere
right in front of your eyes.
So you really aren't...
Please... Even if it's just while
you're in town, pretend to be Tony.
L-Long time, no see!
I went to the trouble to
see you in the afternoon,
but your manners are sadly lacking.
I thought about saying something,
but by then you were gone.
What could I do?
Well, shall we get right down to
business and pick up where we left off?
Easy, easy, easy... hold your horses...
I did this for your benefit.
That old woman and young guy
have been snooping around the ruins...
I thought, "Boy, this is dangerous," so
I very nicely had the brat call you over.
So if you've got the motivation,
why not just take care of that
dangerous devil at the ruins yourself?
That's crazy talk! I make it a
point to only fight weaklings.
If this doesn't concern you at
all, you could've just not come.
I just wanted to see your face one last time!
You're so scary...
In the end, you were drawn here
by the smell of a devil, weren't you?
Tony, you sure are an
early riser, aren't you?
I'll put some coffee on.
Don't do it. Don't try to summon that devil.
What are you saying?
What are you planning to do if
you're actually able to summon the devil?
If humans were capable of defeating them,
that tragedy 20 years ago
never would've happened.
Or have you been relying
on me from the beginning?
I have no intention of asking for your help.
Don't play tougher than you are.
I can lower my fees for you if need be.
I've made preparations.
That thing won't even
serve as a security blanket.
Does Elise have any idea
what you're planning to do?
This has nothing to do with her.
You have to understand, Tony!
This problem concerns me too!
That's Tony, isn't it?
How do you know?
You were just here yesterday.
You came alone today?
He's at school.
I see...
Tell me where those ruins are.
Hmm?
Earnest is planning on summoning that devil.
He wants to clear you
and your mother's names.
No, you're wrong.
Tony?
I'm not Tony.
Sure, when I was a showoff little kid,
there were times when I
used the name "Tony"...
But I am not the Tony
you two are looking for.
My name is Dante.
Don't worry. Just while I'm in
town, I'll play his friend Tony.
So tell me where I can find those ruins.
Yavalk, Dhimli, Vashatoo...
Wanudune, Shekto, Kaopoke, Umyu...
I can't move!
Tony?!
This is the devil?
Are you Dante?
--Huh?
--What if I am?
Tony?
As you're the son of Sparda,
I was wondering what you'd look like.
But it looks like you're still just a kid.
So you'll cut me some slack then?
Tony... you're...
Get out of here!
I'm the one this bastard wants!
So you are! I'm here for your blood, Dante!
Because the moment I have your blood,
the blood of a man born of human and devil,
I can stand lord above the demon world!
20 years ago...
The reason that devil
attacked our town is that it...
wanted you... Tony...
Where's the devil?!
It's all right now. There are no devils.
I saw one!
What am I doing here?
You collapsed at the ruins,
and so Dante brought you here.
Dante?
Where?! Where is he?!
He just left...
Wait! You devil!
Stop it! He's not Tony!
You! If you hadn't been here, none
of those people would have died!
It's all your fault!
That devil destroyed this
town looking for you!
Earnest...
You deceived me and Ms. Margaret!
I'll never forgive you!
Neither will those who died! Do you hear me?!
Don't you ever come back here again!
If you ever do, I'll kill you for sure!
I saw it all. Humans
really are selfish creatures.
They're more horrid than devils.
If you hadn't been there, that town would be
getting devoured by devils right about now
and there would be an ocean of blood.
What are you trying to do?
Something that'll be of use to you.
I don't mind gambling.
For one thing, the tension of
those win-or-lose situations
is similar in some ways to the
feeling I get when I hunt devils.
In the end, I guess I just can't
be satisfied with a "normal life."
But a person should never
do anything excessively.
There's nothing more stupid
than gambling oneself into debt.
Even worse if you go so
far as to lose your life...